http://www.uml.edu/privacy-policy.aspx

Skip to Main Content
Privacy Policy
University of Massachusetts Lowell Terms of Use/Privacy Policy
PLEASE READ THESE TERMS AND CONDITIONS OF USE ("Terms of Use" or "Terms") CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE.Privacy StatementThe University of Massachusetts Lowell respects the privacy of visitors to its Site to the extent permitted by United States, state and federal laws.  This Privacy Statement informs you of what information is collected by this Site and websites with the domain "www.uml.edu" and how the information is used.  Other University of Massachusetts websites may adopt different privacy statements or policies.Your use of websites is subject to the privacy statement of the providers of those websites. You are encouraged to be aware when you leave this Site to read the privacy statement on each website you visit. You can tell you are leaving this Site by looking at the URL of the destination site.When you access the UMass Lowell Home Page ("www.uml.edu"), and all pages within the Site, your visit is not tracked by UMass Lowell using your individual name or any other identifiable personal information. However, this site does utilize Google AdWords, Facebook, LinkedIn, and other software that may track and collect information from your device from the time you access our Site. The information automatically collected is subject to their privacy policies. Blackboard LearnBlackboard CollaborateCall RailDoubleclick Ad ExchangeGoogleHubspotPardotSalesforceSite ImproveSignalTradeDeskWebtrends Privacy Policy | Cookie PolicySome computer information and automatic and optional information is collected by third party vendors, such as Google AdWords and Facebook when you access the Site. This information is subject to the privacy policies of these services. Information collected may include:Internet domain and Internet address of the computer, mobile device or other device you use to access the Site.Essential technical information collected includes the identification of the page or service you are requesting, type of browser and operating system you are using; and the date and time of access.Optional information is collected only if you choose to send it. For example, if you choose to complete an online form, register for an event, or send an email. Optional information that is collected may include:Your name, e-mail address, and the content of your e-mail.EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)This website is intended for general use and is viewable on the internet throughout the world. If you are visiting this website from the European Union (EU), personal information you provide to UMass Lowell may not be subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The GDPR replaces the Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC and was designed to strengthen data privacy protections for EU residents. Should you have additional questions or need information regarding GDPR’s impact and its application to personal information provided to the University visit the GDPR website.Terms and Conditions of UseBy using and/or accessing this website, signified by the URL "www.uml.edu", you agree to these Terms of Use and Privacy Statement. This website is the official website of the University of Massachusetts Lowell, (the "Site"). The Site is owned by the University of Massachusetts Lowell and operated by the University of Massachusetts Lowell University Relations (referred to as "we," "us," or "our.").  By using or accessing this Site you agree that you have read these Terms and Privacy Policy and agree to be bound by and comply with them. If you do not agree to be bound by these Terms and Privacy Statement, please exit this Site.We reserve the right, at our discretion, to change, modify, add, or remove portions of the Terms of Use and Privacy Policy at any time. Please review these Terms and Privacy Policy periodically for changes.Except as noted, the information below applies to the Site, consisting of designated Web pages or publications of the UMass Lowell, its departments, administrative offices, divisions, and other units pertaining to the Site.You may also find within the Site publications created and maintained by UMass Lowell faculty, staff, students, student organizations and others for which neither UMass Lowell is responsible for the content and administration. These pages and their content, including but not limited to factual statements and opinions, are the sole responsibility of their creators and do not represent, explicitly or implicitly, positions, policies or opinions of the UMass Lowell. Although UMass Lowell encourages compliance with all policies and practices at such websites, UMass Lowell serves only as a provider of Internet-related services in these cases.Disclaimer of WarrantyWhile we try to keep the information on the website as accurate as possible, we disclaim any warranty concerning its accuracy, timeliness and completeness, and any other warranty, express or implied, including warranties of merchantability or fitness for a particular purpose.Limitation of LiabilityThe user assumes all responsibility and risk for the use of this Site and the Internet in general.  Under no circumstances shall the University of Massachusetts, its employees, president, Trustees, agents, representatives, affiliates, or anyone involved in creating or maintaining this Site be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, special or consequential damages, lost profits, or other damages whatsoever including, without limitation, damages that result from; the use or inability to use or access to the Site and/or any other websites which are linked to this Site; reliance by a visitor on any information obtained via the Site; or mistakes, omissions, interruptions, deletion of files, viruses, errors, defects, or any failure of performance, communications failure, theft, destruction or unauthorized access. In states which do not allow the above limitations of liability, liability shall be limited to the greatest extent permitted by law.Copyright and Acceptable UseAll text, images, graphics, logos and information contained on the Site is the intellectual property of UMass Lowell, unless otherwise identified. You must obtain written permission in order to reproduce, distribute, perform, display, or license a given work. Whether or not a website includes a statement about copyright, the U.S. copyright act provides protection for such works, and they may not be used or reproduced without permission.UMass Lowell is not responsible for any errors in the material provided on the Site and shall not be liable for any damages of any kind arising from the use of any material found at this Site or on any other Site with the "www.uml.edu" domain. Links may be directed to these pages, but images, logos, maps, may not be copied and/or posted for any reason.Logos, Designs, and TrademarksCertain names, words, titles, phrases, logos, icons, graphics or designs appearing in the pages of this website may constitute registered or unregistered trademarks or trade names of the University. The display of any of the above trademarks or trade names on pages of this website does not imply that any license has been granted to any third party to use the trademarks or trade names of the University.All external commercial use of the University marks must be licensed or approved by the University Trademark and Licensing Administration prior to use. Use includes the manufacture and distribution of all commercial and consumer products, advertising, promotion, domain names, Internet commercial use, websites and all University marks used in conjunction with commercial ventures or Intellectual property licenses. If you wish to apply for permission to use the University's marks for a commercial use or venture, please contact the University of Massachusetts Trademark and Licensing Administration at 413-577-8126.Cookies and Web BeaconsUMass Lowell utilizes "cookies" to enhance the experience on our Site and for marketing purposes. Cookies are text files we place in your computer's, mobile device’s, tablet’s or other device’s browser to help us improve our access to our Site and identify repeat visitors to our Site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of visitors to our Site to enhance the experience on our Site. We us cookies to understand Site usage and to improve the content and offerings on our Site. We also may use cookies to offer you products, programs, or services, or to provide you with personalized online display advertising tailored to your interests. In addition, we may use the services of third parties to collect and use anonymous information about your visits to and interactions with our Site through the use of technologies such as cookies to personalize advertisements. Cookies do not store personal information about you, unless you voluntarily provide it. UMass Lowell does not collect any personal information about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an email, completing a request or event registration form, or completing an online application.You may refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. Your browser may also be set not to accept cookies.UMass Lowell may collect a limited set of non-personally identifiable information about you to help manage our online advertising and promotions, we or our third party advertising providers use "web beacons" (also known as "clear gifs" and "pixel tags"), in conjunction with cookies as non-personal information. Web beacons are small transparent graphic images used by many websites in connection with cookies. For more information about the use of this technology by us and our third-party advertising service providers, including how to opt out of these technologies, please visit the Consumer Opt Out page on Network Advertising Initiative and Adobe Digital Marketing Suite Opt Out page.The University of Massachusetts Lowell may use remarketing pixels created by Google AdWords, DoubleClick, LinkedIn, Facebook, or other services to show you ads or relevant content on these channels or across the Internet. These marketing pixels collect information about the websites you visit, which are stored by these services and then provides you ads on other websites. You may manually opt out of these services or the vendor’s use of cookies by visiting their websites. Here are links on how to opt out of third-party services that may or may not be utilized on this website:DoubleClick opt-outGoogle Ad SettingsNetwork Advertising Initiative opt-outSignal Opt-outAdmissions & Enrollment Texting RecipientsFor applicants that have opted-in to text messages:We may text you up to four times per month in regard to your application.Message and data rates may apply.Text HELP to 23198 for help or email admissions@uml.edu.Text STOP to 23198 for cancel.Carriers are not liable for delayed or undelivered messages.Social Media FeaturesOur Site includes Social Media functions, including Facebook buttons, and Widgets, developed and maintained by university-approved vendors and/or third-party services. These features may collect your IP address, pages you visited, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Sites. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.University Information Technology ServicesUniversity Information Technology Services (UITS) establishes, monitors and enforces policies for use of University computing and information technology resources which include, but are not limited to, equipment, software, networks, data, and telephones whether owned, leased, or otherwise provided.Links to Other SitesThis Site contains links to other sites. This Site is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other websites. We encourage you to be aware when you leave this Site to read the privacy statements to other websites.Updates to This Privacy StatementUMass Lowell has the right to make changes or additions to this Statement at any time. Please review this Statement periodically for changes. If you have questions regarding this Statement, please contact webcontent@uml.edu.Contacting the WebsiteIf you have any questions about the Terms and Conditions of Use or the Privacy Statement, the practices of this Site or your dealings with this Site, please contact University Relations by emailing webcontent@uml.edu.
Quick Links
Request Information
Apply
Check Application Status
Visit
